# **Mark Sherman**

2115 SE 72nd Ave, Portland OR 97215 831.320.6209

markxyzsherman@gmail.com

Seeking a position in ...

## **Systems Engineer**

Software Engineer experienced in developing and maintaining release engineering environments. Ten years experience developing and maintaining software tools to support source code management, product and patch creation, quality control, testing and verification of various Unix products on multiple platforms. Excellent communication skills. Effective in team environments. Team lead for worldwide teams

#### Technical Skills

**Platforms**: Solaris Unix

Languages: Perl, SH, KSH, CSH, c, assembler, Pascal

**Tools**: Teamware, CVS, buildpatch, Hudson, Ant, Mercurial, Git, Subversion

#### Professional Experience

### **Mathematics High School Teacher**

Mt. Hood Community College – High School Services 2011 - present

Taught algebra at all levels

Taught geometry at all levels

Developed self taught learning lab/independent study.

### **Software Release Engineer**

2013 - 2014

TextPlus – Marina Del Rey. California

Responsible for development and support continuous build environment and build scripts.

- Developed CI build under Jenkins
- Redesigned and implemented new build scripts for mobile app
- Monitored backup systems
- Supported and enhanced various build team build scripts
- Created and maintained documentation on build processes

## **Software Release Engineer**

1998 - 2008

Sun Microsystems, Santa Clara, CA

Responsible for development and maintenance of distributed build environments for OTP and SunCluster port to Linux. Responsibilities included:

- Lead release engineer for multiple development teams distributed worldwide
- Creation of patch environment for released Open Telecommunications Platform 2.0 product
- Migration of source code repositories from Teamware to Mercurial
- Creation and support of build environments in Europe, India, and the US
- Creation and documenting release engineering processes
- Training and support for development of release engineering environments

- Implementation of new build structure using Ant
- Implementation of consistent processes and tools to support development integration into a variety of repositories
- Automate build tools to ensure all build systems worldwide are synced daily and operational
- Initial evaluator for release engineering bugs for Open Telecommunications Platform
- Updated and created bug tracking structure using Bugster db for maintenance gates
- Design and code build and patch tools

#### Software/Release Engineer

2000 - 2007

Sun Microsystems, Menlo Park, CA

Responsible for development and maintenance of build environments, patch tools, training, and support of multiple teams in Prague and Menlo Park.

- Designed dual gate patch creation processes and tools for Solaris 10 Update 4.
- Developed patch audit tools and integrated them into patch build environment.
- Increased the number of patches that could be cut per person per day saving one or two full time resources.
- Automated Solaris patch build environments to allow for daily patch creation with no down time or delays.
- Created patch audits to reduce and eliminate patch creation errors.
- Lead release engineer for Solaris 9 update 6.
- Created patch gates for SunMC products 2.51,3.0, 3.1 and 3.5.
- Draft White Paper on streamlining feature gate management implemented in Solaris 10 U4.
- Lead of the tech committee
- Mentor to distributed teams new staff members

**Buildmaster** 1998-2000

Sun Microsystems, Menlo Park, CA

Responsible for the building of Solaris compilers, debuggers, assemblers, make, sccs, libC, math libraries and compiler patches. Restricted engineer for the Merced (Itanium) x86 project.

- Buildmaster and source code manager for Merced (Itanium C compiler).
- Buildmaster for Solaris Compiler Tools
- Patch gatekeeper for Solaris Compiler Tools
- Developed automatic build and package of source code for Solaris product deliveries
- Lead buildmaster and technical lead
- Designed automated Docs build environment integrating java help sets into nightly builds
- Redesigned build environment to reduce build times by 40%
- Delivered tools builds on time

#### **Systems Programmer**

1986-1990

Bank of America, San Francisco CA

- Operating systems programmer.
- Responsible for the maintenance and support of a customized OS and serial communications system. Provide fail safe 24/7 operation.
- Manage store and forward services with full backup and recovery support.
- Designed and implemented real time message switch testing system used by 7 key corporate divisions.
- Enhanced end of day/months audits.

#### Badger Meter, Richmond CA

Developed custom operating system and test software for various telcos. Software provided some of the first remote testing of telephone wires, pinpointing breaks in lines. Hardware and software were developed in house.

### Math and Computer Science Junior High Teacher

Salinas Union High School District

1997 - 1998

- Taught 7<sup>th</sup> grade introduction to computer technology
- Developed self paced computer programming course
- Developed curriculum for video and robotics

### Gilroy Unified School District

1994 - 1997

- Taught 7<sup>th</sup>/8<sup>th</sup> grade pre-algebra
- Designed and taught 7<sup>th</sup> grade computer literacy course

#### Alum Rock School District

1993 - 1994

• Taught 6<sup>th</sup>, 7<sup>th</sup>, 8<sup>th</sup> pre-algebra courses

Pajaro Unified School District

1991 - 1992

• Designed and taught 3<sup>rd</sup> and 4<sup>th</sup> grade computer literacy course

## **Software Engineer**

1979 - 1981

Development project to build a mainframe with multiple CPUs utilizing shared memory and local memory.

## **President Prunedal Mutual Water Company**

2001 - 2005

Managed small water company. Insured compliance with county, state and federal regulations to deliver safe drinking water to one of the largest water systems in Prunedale California. Grade III water operator, responsible for tank, well, and distribution lines. Wrote monthly newsletter. Performed scheduled water tests. Wrote grants for water system upgrades and pilot projects.

Education and Training	
Computer Science Instructor	1986 – 1987
San Francisco City College	
Taught structured programming.	
San Diego State University	1981 - 1982
Taught various programming courses	

Education and Training		
San Diego State University	Computer Science Masters Program	1981 - 1982
University of California, Irvine	BS Information and Computer Science	1977 - 1979
Santa Monica City College (Harvard by the Sea), California		1974 – 1977
San Francisco State University	K-8 Teaching Credential	1990 – 1991

References available upon request